KISHORE VASAN

Boston, United States

github.com/kishorevasan & vasan.k@northeastern.edu & kishorevasan.github.io

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

A highly motivated and spirited learner who is excited about what life offers. My research builds and uses tools from network science, temporal networks, and data visualization to study the clinical sciences and the funding ecosystem.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

 $September\ 2020\ -\ Present$

PhD in Network Science

Boston, Massachussets

Research direction: Funding ecosystem in the clinical sciences

Advisor: Albert-Laszlo Barabasi

University of Washington

September 2016 - June 2020

Bachelor of Science

Seattle, Washington

Major: Informatics - Data Science; Minor: Quantitative Science

Advisor: Jevin West

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Python, R, mySQL, d3.JS, Java, React, HTML

Software & Tools RStudio, Gephi, Cytoscape, networkx, matplotlib, pandas, pytorch

EXPERIENCE

Center for Complex Networks Research, Network Science Institute

Sept 2020 - Present

Graduate Research Associate

Risk and reward, failure and success in clinical trials

September 2020 - Present

- · Clinical trials are a risky endeavor, making it high reward, but not all clinical trials are successful. Yet, the individual choices by funders affects the collective exploration of human diseases.
- · The goal of the project is to decipher the motivations in why funders fund they way the do and formulate strategies that could improve the present clinical pipeline.

DataLab, Information School

September 2017 - August 2020

Undergraduate Research Associate

Collective dynamics in co-funding of clinical trials 2020

July 2019 - August

- · Assessing the scientific impact of different funding strategies in clinical trials. The goal is to untangle the relationship between funding agencies through a co-funding network.
- · Funded by the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation.

Measuring scientific buzz using keywords

July 2018 - June 2019

- · Compains the applicability of keywords and abstracts in describing research trends. I discovered that keywords are a powerful resource for identifying hot topics than abstracts.
- · Funded through scholarship from the Mary Gates Endowment.

Mapping cross-departmental collaboration at UW

September 2017 - August 2018

- · How impactful are multi-departmental collaboration at a large scale public university? We discovered an effect of compartmentalization where departments that collaborate together, also cite each other.
- · I worked on disambiguation of departmental and institutional affiliations of authors over 60k papers

Information School, University of Washington

Spring 2018 - Spring 2019

Teaching Assistant, INFO 201 - Data Visualization using R.

· As a TA for over 100 students, I conducted weekly lab sessions, answered online questions, and graded weekly assignments. The course covers source control and interactive data visualization principles.

Genpact Inc.

June 2017 - August 2017

Data Science Intern

- · Enhancing customer care analytics by automatic emotion recognition system by extracting voice features and unsupervised topic clustering of GM Financial chat transcripts using latent semantic analysis.
- · Worked in a team of 4 people and presented a proof of concept to the upper management.

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Publications

The hidden influence of communities in collaborative funding of clinical science Aug 2021 Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

Royal Society Open Science

Quantifying NFT-driven networks in crypto art

September 2021

Kishore Vasan, Milan Janosov, and Albert-Laszlo Barabasi.

Scientific Reports (Under Review)

Quantifying drug target exploration in clinical trials

TBA

Kishore Vasan, Deisy Gysi, and Albert-Laszlo Barabasi.

In Prep, Target journal: Nature Drug Discovery

Conference Papers

SciSight: Combining faceted navigation and research group detection for COVID-19 exploratory scientific search $${\rm May}\ 2020$$

Tom Hope, Jason Portenoy*, Kishore Vasan*, Jonathan Borchardt*, Eric Horvitz, Daniel Weld, Marti Hearst, and Jevin West.

Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) 2020 systems track. Online.

Is together better? Examining scientific collaboration across multiple authors, departments and institutions. August 2018

Lovenoor Aulck, Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

Knowledge Discovery and Data mining (KDD): BigScholar workshop 2018. London, UK.

Measuring scientific buzz.

March 2019

Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

^{*} - denotes equal contribution

Information Schools Conference (iConference) 2019 as a poster. Washington, DC.

Should granting agencies actively engage in co-funding?

January 2020

Kishore Vasan, Carl Bergstrom, and Jevin West.

NetSci-X 2020 as a poster. Tokyo, Japan.

PRESENTATIONS

Research Exposed! Population Health Initiative (PHI) panel

March 4, 2020

Undergraduate Research Symposium Presented work on collaborative funding

May 15, 2020

SERVICE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Mary Gates Research Scholarship

2018 - 2019

- · A highly selective award given to undergrads at the University of Washington pursuing research.
- · I received this award to develop techniques to map research trends using author keywords.

Society of Network Scientists, UW

Fall 2019 - Summer 2020

Co-Founder, Vice President

- · A campus wide initiative with an aim to promote and encourage research in network science. The organization acts as a platform for fellow researchers to interact and collaborate.
- · We host weekly reading groups on social networks, panel discussions, and invite distinguished speakers.
- · The group also serves an eScience Special Interest Group (SIG) on networks, and a local chapter of The Society of Young Network Scientists (SYNS).

Informatics Admission Committee

Spring 2019

- · Helped review undergraduate applicants for Informatics, a competitive major.
- · Comprehensively reviewed the applicant based on personal statement, intent to major, and grades.

CLASSROOM PROJECTS

Crawling Wikipedia Graph

April 2019 - June 2019

Exploring the edit dynamics of users in Wikipedia

Statistical Analysis of Social Networks

- · Mining large graphs reveals information; temporal network of the same reveal evolution. However, performing novel algorithms on these large graphs can be computationally expensive. We need methods that can provide an un-biased sample that would be representative of the underlying large network.
- · In this work, we evaluated different random walks by crawling a large online editing network, Wikipedia.
- · Our *findings* include simple random walk is ineffective when sampling graphs with high tailed distribution, and re-weighted random walk outperforms other methods for graph sampling.

Does location affect Food Security?

April 2018 - June 2018

Analyzing Food Security in the United States

Population Health Informatics

- · Motivation comes from the fact that places along the coast have ease of access to food than the places in the middle of the land, especially during unfriendly seasons.
- · Looked at Food Security through the lens of Food Accessibility, Food Nutrition and Food Expenditure.
- · Used several visualizations and performed K-Means clustering of states within United States to explore geo-location impact on Food Security. Deliverables included a short paper and a R Shiny app.
- Discovered evidence of similar food security levels along geographical lines, in particular 3 main regions in the United States were observed.

Does President Trump's tweets have an impact on Forex?

Focus on US-South Korea exchange rate

October 2017 - December 2017 Core methods in Data Science

- · Worked in a team of 4 to find out if there is an effect on the US-South Korea exchange rate every time President Trump tweets about North Korea.
- · Used twitter API to gather approximately 6800 tweets. Parsed out all tweets that pertains to North Korea. Performed Difference-in-Differences econometrics method with Canada as our control state.
- · Preliminary results showed that the value of South Korea currency decreases with every tweet. That is, the value of US currency goes up.

COURSEWORK

Northeastern University

PHYS 5116 - Complex networks and application I

NETS 6116 - Complex networks and application II

PHYS 7332 - Graph machine learning

POLS 7334 - Social network analysis

NETS 7341 - Network economics (In Progress)

PHYS 7335 - Dynamical processes in complex networks (In Progress)

University of Washington

QSCI 403 - Introduction to resampling inference

QSCI 482 - Statistical inference in applied research I

QSCI 483 - Statistical inference in applied research II

QSCI 497 - Complex analysis using agent based models

STAT 567 - Statistical analysis of social networks

MATH 308 - Matrix algebra with applications

MATH 309 - Linear analysis

MATH 324 - Advanced multi-variable calculus I

INFO 371 - Advanced methods in data science

INFO 430 - Advanced database design and management

CSE 373 - Data structures and algorithms

CSE 415 - Introduction to artificial intelligence